This exercise is called standing twist, and we're going to use a towel for this exercise.
And what we're going to do is utilize a bath towel, or a hand towel, so that you can keep your posture nice and upright.
So with your feet about hip width apart, soften your knees, extend your arms, and simply twist from your torso.
Now as you're twisting, think about pulling on the ends of the towel, and that will pull your shoulder blades into place.
And we're really improving the posture all at the same time.
This is a great exercise for the core, while you're strengthening your upper back muscles.
So when you breathe, you want to inhale to prepare, exhale as you twist.
Inhale as you bring the towel back to the front, exhale as you twist.
And if you really focus on blowing out you'll really get a great abdominal workout, and then you'll begin to really feel it in your upper body at the same time.
So perform this exercise for about a minute, and then just lower your arms down and rest.
And that is your standing twist.